<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>housewife_hacker</title><link href="http://housewifehacker.com" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://housewifehacker.com/feeds/Startup.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://housewifehacker.com</id><updated>2012-05-31T00:00:00-04:00</updated><entry><title>Investment Aversion</title><link href="http://housewifehacker.com/investment-aversion.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-05-31T00:00:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Jessie Anderson</name></author><id>http://housewifehacker.com/investment-aversion.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;We have many well developed ideas for businesses that we could be launching as startups. One of our ideas is especially low risk, has a high earnings potential, is related to our CTO's work experience, and is in a fun and exciting industry. Naturally, we've decided to focus our energy on that product, so that we can earn enough money to be able to work on other projects later. That idea is our conference management system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the reasons our conference management system is so well thought out is that we have not been shy to discuss our ideas with other entrepreneurs. We don't fear our idea being stolen because we are confident that no other person or team could complete our product better than ourselves. We've also analyzed the competition and learned from related industries. A couple times while we've discussed the software with someone who has achieved a high level of financial success, they have expressed interest in investing. Many young people with a startup would give up a large portion of their company for some cash, but not us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Giving equity is messy and time consuming for a couple reasons. First, you have to invest the time to know your potential investor's goals. If your investor wants the company to change or go in a different direction, it's kind of hard to tell them no after they've given you money. You need to have compatible goals and motivation to work well with an investor. Second, you have to determine if the investor truly adds value to your project. Sure, cash is value. But other than cash, can they offer connections? Do they have experience in your industry? Do they want to be on the board, involved in company decisions as a mentor? Third, you have to get everything in writing and pay for lawyers and accountants to organize ownership and vesting schedule contracts. You may spend two or three weeks ironing out details with a potential investor, only for them to change their minds the day before signing the contract.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then once you go through the laborous process of securing your investor, the politics starts. Be prepared to explain every business expense, ask permission for every new hire, and justify any changes to the business plan. Instead of just making changes to your product to attract more business, everything is dependent on metrics. If a change improved revenue, you better be able to prove it. If you disagree with an idea or a hire suggested by your investor, you need to have spreadsheets, dollar signs, and a presentation prepared to be convincing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Startups without investment do face a lot of risk and challenges. But as a reward for being truly bootstrapped, they are incredibly mobile and dynamic. Smaller, lighter objects can change directions faster than objects with greater mass. Small teams operating out of a shared apartment can adapt much quicker than a large organization that requires board meetings and weekly email updates. An investor may just become an extra phone call or hoop to jump through before acting on a necessary innovation or pivot. A good investor is like love. It will happen when you aren't actively looking for it, it will be harmoneous, and you would never want to be without them. I would not be averse to a truly beneficial investor, but we're not eager to find our angel just yet. I'd rather be cautious of involving other people in our plans and keep the equity to ourselves.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="investment"></category><category term="strategy"></category></entry><entry><title>We Got In!</title><link href="http://housewifehacker.com/we-got-in.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-05-25T00:00:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Jessie Anderson</name></author><id>http://housewifehacker.com/we-got-in.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Today, about two months after the round four applications for StartUp Chile (www.startupchile.org) closed, the accepted 100 teams were announced. Our team was one of the chosen to recieve 20.000.000 chilean pesos ($40,000 US) over a sixth month time period to start our business in Chile. The money is not tied to any exchange of equity. However, the government does not simply hand over cash either. The program requires us to spend our own money, getting reimbursed up to 90% of each expense for a total of $40,000 over the six month period. We also have to volunteer our time for various causes within the community that directly benefits the local population. Most people in the program earn credit by speaking about entrepreneurship. Our friend George Cadena, founder and CEO of StudioSnaps, taught an entrepreneurship course at local universities and has continued to teach and mentor beyond the duration of his program requirements. We will probably earn our credit by teaching programming and putting on events with our event planning software. Most of the StartUp Chile events are currently using Welcu. We believe we can replace them with our superior knowledge of the industry, our higher standards of quality, and our exceptional technology. Their goal is to be acquired, and it shows. We aim to manage the entire event planning process, from communicating with clients, contracting vendors, organizing speakers, collecting registrations, and analyzing reports. We LOVE the event planning business. Our passion, experience, and quality should make us a serious threat in Chile, South America, and the rest of the world.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="Chile"></category><category term="Investment"></category><category term="EventRay"></category></entry></feed>